And uh if you don't mind if you can be
up standing for the reading of God's
word.
Genesis chapter 1 from verse 26 to 28 is
my text this morning.
God is speaking
in the book of Genesis, the book of
beginnings.
And the Bible says, "Then God said,
let us make man in our image, according
to our likeness. Let them have dominion
over the fish of the sea, over the birds
of the air, and over the kettle, over
all the earth,
and uh over every cripping thing that
crips on the earth."
So God created man in his own image
in the image of God. He created him.
Male
and female
he created
them.
Then God blessed them.
And God said to them, "Be fruitful and
multiply.
Fill the earth and subdue it.
Have dominion over the fish of the sea,
over the birds of the air,
and over every living thing that moves
on the earth." Father, in the name of
Jesus, thank you for the reading of your
word. bless it to our heart.
I pray oh God that you give us a
revelation from the scriptures Lord that
your name will be glorified.
Let your will be done Lord
according to these scriptures
in Jesus name I pray somebody say amen
and amen. You may be seated in the
presence of the Lord.
Last Sunday, I announced that I'm going
to be starting a series on dominion this
Sunday.
I'm hoping by the grace of God that I'm
going to be doing this series for the
next one month or so
because this series is important
to me and to God.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen,
Dominion
is God's original plan,
intention
for mankind.
The first words that God spoke
concerning man reveal his divine
purpose.
Before
God could give man a job,
before God could give man a family,
before God could give man even a
location,
God
gave the mandate
and the mandate was let them have
dominion.
For you see, man was not created to be a
victim of circumstances.
Man was not created to be a victim of
fear, sin,
or the powers of darkness.
Man was not created just to go around
like a victim who's constantly under
attack from the vicissitudes of life.
Man was created from day one
and given the mandate before even he saw
the face of the earth. The mandates
to have dominion.
For you see, dominion is not about
oppression
or control
or manipulation
or mistreating people
or stepping on people's toes.
It has nothing to do
with all of that.
Dominion has to do with reflecting God's
rule,
God's character,
God's purpose
in every area of your life.
God has blessed me for many years to be
a pastor, a shepherd
from my early 20s.
Being in church, being raised in church,
I've seen and I've heard a lot.
Many prayers that I hear are totally
unbiblical.
For instance,
Christians praying for victory.
God gave you the victory long time ago.
You were born
again to walk, operate,
function
in the victory of Jesus Christ.
It is unbiblical for you to pray for
victory.
God has given you glory.
You just need to read the book of John
and understand that God gave you glory.
He says the glory you have given to me,
I have given to them.
So all you need to do is to walk in the
victory of Jesus. Somebody say amen.
>> All you need to do is to operate in the
victory of Jesus.
Some of the prayers that people pray in
church are totally out of ignorance. I'm
sorry to say so.
But if you get to understand who you are
and what God has done in your life and
the mandate that God has given to you as
a child of God,
some of these prayers that we pray out
of ignorance will just drop off.
Brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen,
God already
called you to live, to walk, to operate,
to function in dominion.
So
dominion
is God's idea.
Look at your neighbor this morning and
tell them dominion is God's idea.
Or please tell them like you really
believe it. Dominion is God's idea.
Tell them for the third time as if they
are deaf and shout to them and tell them
dominion is God's idea.
>> Oh yeah.
Genesis chapter 1 and verse 26 says,
"Let them have dominion."
Psalm
8 verse 4-6 says, "Thou
made us him to have dominion over the
works
of thy hands."
Dominion did not originate with man.
It originated with God.
Before man was formed, God already
determined his purpose.
Miles Monroe, God bless his soul, taught
about purpose
and taught that before a manufacturer
manufactures any item, he has purpose in
mind.
You cannot use a microphone which the
purpose of a microphone is to use to
speak.
You cannot use it to dig. That is not
its purpose.
A car is meant to function to take you
from point A to point B.
It can't take you to Mars.
And God in heaven before he created man,
he declares the purpose
of making man
and says, "I'm making a man in my own
image and in my own likeness
that he may have dominion
over my works.
Yes.
Psalm 82 and verse 6 says, "I have said
ye are gods
and all of you are children of the most
high." In fact, I need that verse to be
up there because some of you don't even
know it exists. Psalm 82 and verse 6, I
said, "Ye are gods
and all of you are the children
of the most high.
Ladies and gentlemen, brothers and
sisters,
when God creates you of his own
likeness,
he creates you to represent his
authority.
An image reflects
its source. I repeat, an image reflects
its source.
When you go to a mirror, you don't see
somebody else. You see you
alone.
Therefore, man was created to reflect
God's nature,
wisdom,
character,
and government. And I repeat, therefore,
man was created
to reflect God's nature,
wisdom,
character,
and government.
God never intended humanity to be ruled
by fear,
confusion,
or failure.
His
intention was that mankind would govern
creation under his authority.
So that says that dominion is part of
our divine design.
I mean to dominate is part of us. Tap
your neighbor and tell them to dominate
is part of me.
Oh, come on. Tell them to dominate is
PART OF ME. YOU ARE CREATED TO REFLECT
GOD'S GLORY. THAT WHEN YOU LOOK AT ME,
YOU CANNOT HELP BUT SEE THE GOODNESS of
God in the land of the living. Somebody
shout, "Amen."
>> When you look at me, YOU SHOULD SEE GOD
IN ACTION. WHEN YOU look at me, YOU
SHOULD BE ABLE TO SEE GOD WHO HAS
FEARFULLY and wonderfully created me.
When you look at me, YOU SHOULD SEE THE
AUTHORITY OF GOD. WHEN YOU LOOK AT ME,
OH, come on. I'm preaching to SOMEBODY
THIS MORNING. WHEN YOU look at me,
you're not supposed TO BE SEEING FAILURE
AND DISAPPOINTMENT AND FRUSTRATION AND
ALL THE THINGS THAT the demons bring
along with it. WHEN YOU LOOK AT A CHILD
OF GOD, YOU SHOULD BE ABLE TO SEE
DOMINION.
>> I'm preaching this sermon from a very
heavy heart.
this series, I'm preaching it from a
very heavy heart because I see a lot of
Christians walking like nobody's. Uh I
see a lot of Christians who don't even
know WHO THEY ARE. I SEE A LOT OF
CHRISTIANS WHO HAVE NO CLUE of what
Christ has done for them.
This message is one message that I'm
preaching from a bleeding heart.
For if you know what God has done for
you, if you know the mandate
that we have been given,
the mandate of dominion,
Christ
will be glorified
in your life.
Ladies and gentlemen, are you aware that
Adam named the animals in the garden?
Genesis chapter 2 and verse 19 to 20.
AND WHATEVER HE CALLED THE ANIMALS, they
were
dominion.
Joseph governed Egypt.
THE BIBLE SAYS BECAUSE OF JOSEPH,
Egypt was blessed.
DID YOU KNOW THAT SOME COMPANIES ARE
BLESSED BECAUSE YOU ARE THERE?
OH, come on. Talk to me church. Did you
know that some company, I REPEAT, SOME
PLACES YOU'RE WORKING, THEY are blessed
because of you and they are not even
aware. I have seen some companies go
down because somebody left
because they didn't even realize the
person who was bringing the blessing was
a child of God who is blessed and
anointed and when they leave the
blessing left with them. The whole
COUNTRY OF EGYPT WAS blessed because of
Joseph
dominion in government.
SOMEBODY SAY, "That's who I am."
>> That's who I am.
>> If I'm going to preach this message, you
have to give me some steam. You know,
are you hearing me? You have to give me
some steam. I know some of you just sit
like you're watching a movie theater. I
am not uh Chuck Norris. Please, I am a
I'm a preacher. Look at your neighbor.
I'm He's preaching to us. I didn't come
to act here. I came to preach the
gospel. And sometimes I preach when I'm
not even feeling well, but I preach
dominion.
David had dominion because of the
anointing of God.
2 Samuel 8:6, the Lord gave David
victory wherever he went.
Wherever he went, somebody say that's my
portion. Wherever he went, God gave him
victory. Wherever he went, I don't care
where they put you. They can take you to
Mandera, you'll have victory. THEY CAN
TAKE YOU TO HIS SOLO, YOU'LL HAVE
VICTORY. OH, COME ON, SOMEBODY. WHEREVER
HE WENT, TAP YOUR NEIGHBOR AND TELL THEM
THE ANOINTING OF GOD GIVES YOU DOMINION.
THAT WHEREVER YOU GO, YOU WILL HAVE UH
THE DOMINION THAT GOD HAS INTENDED FOR
WHEREVER HE WENT.
>> DOMINION. DO YOU SERVE THE SAME GOD
THESE PEOPLE SERVED OR WHAT?
David ruled Israel,
defeated enemies,
and expanded the kingdom.
May expansion be your portion this
morning.
>> Now, this service, you'll have to say a
lot of amens because of what I'm
preaching about. Amen. I say, "May
expansion be your portion this morning."
Amen.
>> Come on, somebody say I'm tapping into
the expansion.
>> God has called me to dominate, to have
dominion. I have no problem. I'll not
make any apologies. God has anointed me
to have dominion. Stop making apologies
for what God is doing in your life. Uh
don't live like an apology when God has
anointed you to have dominion. Uh you
have been called to have dominion, CHILD
OF GOD. WALK LIKE SOMEBODY WHO HAS
DOMINION. TALK LIKE SOMEBODY WHO HAS
DOMINION. THINK LIKE SOMEBODY WHO HAS
DOMINION. GOD HAS GIVEN YOU THE MANDATE
TO HAVE DOMINION.
>> Even if I don't say anything, I can go
home now.
I AM SICK AND TIRED OF SEEING Christians
doing nothing.
Somebody say, "OUCH."
I AM SICK AND TIRED OF SEEING CHRISTIAN
BEGGING. ANOTHER OUCH. I AM SICK AND
TIRED OF SEEING CHRISTIAN BEING AT THE
TAIL END WHEN GOD HAS GIVEN THEM THE
DOMINION. WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU? IT IS
NOT GOD FOR SURE. AND LET ME TELL YOU
SOMETHING I WANT TO SAY HERE. GOD IS NOT
FIGHTING TO DEFEAT THE DEVIL. THE DEVIL
WAS DEFEATED LONG TIME AGO. I'M TELLING
YOU, THE DEVIL HAS COME TO CONFUSE YOU
SO YOU DON'T KNOW WHO you are.
God is not fighting to defeat the devil.
The devil was defeated long time ago.
What's wrong with you now? You can't
tell your neighbor what's wrong with
you. I know there's some guys who are a
bit, you know,
you tell the guy who what's wrong with
you and then look at you.
God
said,
"Let us make man
in our own image."
AN IMAGE IS DRAWN FROM THE source
in our likeness.
AND THEN HE SPECIFIES THE PURPOSE. HE
SAYS SO THAT THEY CAN have
dominion
over the works
of God.
Solomon
had dominion through wisdom. First Kings
chapter 4 and verse 24.
Solomon exercised dominion over the vast
kingdom
because of divine wisdom.
Wisdom
a key to lasting dominion.
I repeat, wisdom a key
to lasting
dominion.
May God give you wisdom this morning.
>> Amen.
Amen.
>> I don't like your amen.
>> Can you shout like you're a Sunday
school ch child here?
>> That's much better.
Wisdom is a principle thing.
Wisdom.
You can have knowledge, but if you don't
have wisdom, you'll mess up.
Are you listening to me?
A lot of people have knowledge but have
no wisdom.
What do you mean bishop?
Wisdom
is the application of knowledge
to know
what to do
at the right time.
So
that means that
you can be saying the right thing at the
wrong time.
Is that true?
One of the things I really liked about
my wife was she had wisdom what to tell
me and when to tell me and how to tell
me.
You you you can say this the same thing,
but if you have no wisdom,
it will rub the person the wrong way.
Hello.
I'm I'm I'm not saying that uh you know
I advocate for violence or anything. I
don't advocate for violence at all.
Zero.
But but if your husband comes from work,
he's tired.
All right?
And you say the wrong thing
at the wrong time. For those of you who
are married,
hello. And that even can be vice versa.
It can be the man saying the wrong thing
to the wife. The results are never the
same.
Come on, talk to me.
Well, come on. Come on. Come on. Come
on. Talk to me.
>> Is that true?
>> SO, TIMING, TIMING, AND WISDOM, THE
APPLICATION OF KNOWLEDGE, KNOWING WHAT
TO SAY AT THE RIGHT TIME. My friend, if
you know what to do at the right time,
you'll get a lot of good stuff.
Are you listening to me? Let me give
some women some wisdom here because, you
know, I think with my white hair
sometimes, you know, I'm qualified to
say some things.
WHY DO WHY WHY WOULD A MAN BE LEAVING
WORK and then uh driving along and
passing even his own gate, DOESN'T WANT
TO GET INTO THE HOUSE UNTIL the woman
sleeps.
SOMEBODY SAY, "OUCH."
I MEAN, THE GUY LEFT HIS OFFICE AND HE'S
JUST DRIVING AROUND AND EVEN HE PASSED
HIS OWN gate
because WHEN THE WHEN THE MAN GOES home
early,
HE KNOWS WHAT HE'S GOING TO GET
AND IT'S NOT GOING TO BE SOMETHING THAT
IS GOING TO BE VERY peaceful or soothing
anyways.
SO THE WOMAN HAS TO have wisdom.
All right? And I'm saying this that it
applies in both ways. Even the man has
to have wisdom.
Hello. Can the man can the man say a
wisdom will give you dominion.
>> Are you listening to me? The application
of wisdom. Tap somebody say the
application of wisdom
will give you dominion.
Knowing what to say
and when to say it
and how
to say it.
I PREACHED A SERMON LONG TIME AGO.
I don't know how many can remember it.
My biggest problem is that I can't
preach a sermon twice because people
remember my sermons.
Uh I don't know whether my sermons are
good or the students are good or one of
the two. But anyways, I preached a
sermon and the sermon was I don't want
Delilah, I want you.
You remember?
And in that sermon, I I don't want
Delilah, I want you. Now, some of you
have got your eyes open.
Jesus Christ, I feel like I could run
away. My God,
Bishop, what are you talking about?
In that sermon, I talked about how
Delila found her way to Samson.
I was talking about actually I was
preaching it it was a a message to
ladies and I was teaching the ladies the
wisdom of course it was wicked wisdom
but it was still wisdom how she was kind
and nice and how she used to call Delila
Delila are you tired Delilah Delilah
please lie on my lap is in the Bible lie
on my lap Delila
Delila
You come from fighting in G Delila.
So why would Sam Samson not go home
knowing he's going to lie on the lap?
Samson will definitely not drive past
gate past the gate.
Definitely not.
Wisdom.
Yes, you have the degrees but you have
no wisdom.
Yes, you have the degrees, but you have
no
wisdom.
People
have dominion
through wisdom. SOLOMON PRAYS AND SAYS,
"OH GOD,
THAT YOU WOULD GIVE ME WISDOM." AND GOD
SAYS FROM THE PARTICLES OF HEAVEN, YOU
HAVE NOT JUST ASKED FOR WISDOM. I'll
give it to you in abundance, but I will
also give you
wealth,
dominion.
Daniel
had dominion in government.
Scripture is Daniel chapter 6 and verse
three. And Daniel distinguished himself
and became a leading administrator in
Babylon.
A leading administrator. I studied the
book of Daniel. Daniel was one of my
best books when I was in college. Daniel
served the four kings.
ADMINISTRATIONS WOULD COME AND GO AND
THEY WOULD RETAIN DANIEL
BECAUSE HE WAS A MAN OF DOMINION WHEN IT
CAME TO GOVERNMENT.
Government dominion
I was waiting for 2027 to come and I
want to hear people saying I'm running
for office in this church.
Yeah.
So the church is going to start
complaining.
All right. And complain about how we
have got bad leaders while they
themselves are doing nothing.
All right. Hello. Hello. doing nothing
and you're complaining. All right?
AND BAD THINGS HAPPEN WHEN GOOD people
keep quiet.
You can say amen.
Talking to Christians, you will not like
me for this, but I'm really going to get
into your skin today. I'm telling you
the truth because I am getting to a
place where I'm wondering if you're
serving the same God Daniel served. If
you're serving the same God David
served, if you're serving the same God
Adam, if you're serving the same God
Joseph served, when I look at the church
and I SEE HOW DOILE IT IS. WE SHOULD BE
OCCUPYING UNTIL HE COMES.
CAN I hear amen? Even
say, "Ouch. It's okay. Me, I'm okay. By
the way, I'm okay. I don't need anybody
to come after this and tell me, "Oh,
Bishop, you're preaching a nice sermon
or you I don't care. I've been preaching
for many years. I do what God has called
me to do. I go home.
I come and be a messenger boy for God."
And I'm telling you, this sermon of
dominion, this series, don't miss one.
It will change your life because the
word of God cannot go forth and return
void. Everything I'm saying is going to
happen. If you have no dominion, you'll
start experiencing dominion. You'll
start thinking dominion. You'll start
dreaming dominion. Can you shout amen?
>> Amen.
>> Why on earth would you want to leave
this earth and then just die and nobody
knows you? No, you never did anything.
You never impacted anything. You never
even built a kiosk. NOTHING. OH MY GOD.
SOMEBODY SAY THAT'S NOT MY PORTION.
>> KIOSK.
OH, we serve a mighty God. We serve a
mighty God. I can't see him in you.
Sorry.
I can't see him in you. I'm sorry. Oh,
we serve a mighty God. We serve a mighty
God. Where is he?
You are begging for bas. Oh, we serve a
mighty God.
WHEN GOD GAVE YOU THE MANDATE
TO BE THE HEAD AND NOT THE TAIL.
Am I annoying you?
I was walking one time in the streets of
Lagos
with my preacher friends
and uh
when we were walking,
we saw a street preacher
trying to preach to a guy who was
begging. This is Lagos.
That street preacher didn't look very
prospered or blessed.
He was just actually looking like the
guy who's begging.
And after the street preacher preached
that that beggar that beggar looked at
the seat preacher and says you know
that God you're preaching me to let him
bless you first then he can bless me.
Church,
we have gotten to a place
where we don't need to talk too much.
Let your life be the preaching platform.
Let your life
be
the salmon.
It is so easy
for an engineer to speak an engineer's
listen.
It is so easy for a doctor to preach and
people listen. Why? He's a doctor. He
doesn't have to preach.
But God HAS CHANGED HIS LIFE.
GOD HAS TRANSFORMED HIM.
I was listening to a testimony today,
this morning just before I got left the
house of a billionaire in Nigeria and he
was being interviewed. He said, "Oh,
you're a billionaire. What can you tell
people who want to be billionaires? One
thing you can tell them and what have
you and what have you." Well, he said
what he wanted to say. Then he said uh
he was asked, "Do you believe in God?"
He said, "Oh, yes. I believe in the
inspiration of God. I believe that God
is the one who gives me power to make
wealth." Such a billionaire speaking.
you will listen.
He said, "I am now buying my fourth
jet."
Somebody who tells you about God like
that, my friend, even before he
finishes, you say, "Yes." Amen.
Dominion.
Ladies and gentlemen, brothers and
sisters, excellence creates
opportunities for dominion. For the
Bible says that uh Daniel distinguished
himself and became a leading
administrator in Babylon because a
spirit of excellence.
A spirit of excellence. Somebody say
that with me. A spirit of excellence.
>> Can you shout it? A spirit of
excellence. I want to know I'm in the
right place.
rested
on him.
Esther had dominion through influence.
Esther chapter 4 and verse 14 to 16. As
queen, Esther used her position to save
an entire nation. That is dominion.
A nation was saved because a lady used
her influence. Dominion is not only
power. It is influence used for God's
purpose. Nemiah
showed dominion through leadership.
Nehemiah chapter 2 and verse 17 to 18.
Nehemiah mobilized the people and
rebuilt Jerusalem walls
despite opposition. Dominion involves
vision, organization, and perseverance.
I repeat, dominion involves vision,
organization,
and perseverance. Dominion involves
vision, organization,
and perseverance.
Deborah,
Judges chapter 4 verse 4-9. Deborah led
Israel as a judge and inspired victory
over their enemies.
It was Dborah who influenced Gideon.
A leader God had called but was timid
and fearful.
Jesus Christ
showed us perfect dominion. Matthew
chapter 28 and verse 18, HE SAYS, "ALL
authority
in heaven and on earth has been given
to me." Jesus demonstrated dominion over
sickness,
demons,
nature,
sin,
and death.
Jesus could stand up and say, "Peace
be still."
Jesus could cast out demons
and demons would leave.
Jesus exhibited the dominion over
nature.
Jesus could multiply the bread and the
fish. Dominion.
Jesus could cleanse THE BLIND EYES.
Jesus could raise the lep cleanse the
lepers and raise the people who are
crippled.
Dominion of a sickness.
AND THEN JESUS TURNS AND SAYS that
dominion I had I'VE GIVEN TO YOU.
HELLO. Are you aware of that? Can you
say amen?
>> Amen.
HE SAYS, "I'VE GIVEN YOU THE SAME POWER,
THE SAME DOMINION,
and that YOU SHALL SAY TO THIS MOUNTAIN,
BE YE REMOVED AND BE CAST TO THE SEA."
WOW.
AND NOTHING SHALL BE IMPOSSIBLE TO YOU.
DOMINION.
WELL,
this dominion I'm talking about
requires identity.
Romans chapter 8 and verse 14-17 says,
"For as many as are led by the spirit of
God, they are the sons of God."
Galatians 4 and:e 7 says, "Wherefore
thou art no more a servant but a son."
I want to repeat that. Wherefore thou
art no more a servant
but a son.
Listen to me now. You cannot
exercise dominion if you don't know who
you are.
I repeat, you cannot exercise dominion
if you don't know who you are. Could
this be the problem in the church today?
That we have myriads of people who don't
know who they are. Could this be the
problem? Why we don't have CHRISTIANS
EXERCISING DOMINION because they are
ignorant
of who they are?
JESUS CHRIST. EVEN BEFORE HE COULD START
his own ministry, heaven had to open up.
AND GOD THE FATHER LOOKS DOWN FROM THE
PARTICLES OF HEAVEN AND SAYS THIS IS UH
MY beloved son uh in whom I AM WELL
PLEASED. THE IDENTITY THAT THIS IS uh my
son.
So do you know who you are?
Don't answer me. Don't answer me.
Do you know who you are?
long time ago when I was doing I think I
think it's even high school teacher used
to ask us you know you should know
why you're here where you're going and
who you are something to that effect who
you are where you're here where you're
going
long time ago secondary school education
secondary school education
Why are you here? Who are you? And where
are you going?
Now, many years later, I'm reading the
Bible and I'm seeing here, you cannot
have dominion if you don't know
your identity. Who are you?
For you see, the greatest weapon of the
enemy is often identity. confusion,
identity confusion. Satan understands
that if he can make you forget who you
are, he can weaken your authority.
I repeat, Satan understands that if he
can make you forget who you are, he can
weaken your authority. Before Jesus
began his ministry, the father declares,
"This is my beloved son." identity
precedes assignment.
Identity precedes assignment.
I know who I am.
I know who I am. I know I'm called to
preach.
I know I'm called to teach God's word.
I'm not a mechanic.
I'm not an athlete.
I'm not a politician.
I am a preacher.
I preach God's word.
I am made to preach.
God created me to preach.
He didn't create me to do other things.
I have dominion in my preaching because
I am not confused of what I'm supposed
to do and who I am. Do you know WHO YOU
ARE? YOU CANNOT HAVE dominion if you
don't know who you are.
And I want to say here that once you
know who you are, please stick to your
lane. Somebody say amen.
>> Amen.
>> Once you know who you are, please stick
to your lane. If you are called to do
business, please do your business. Now,
I'm not saying that you are limited
because I also know that I can do other
things. But please, the major thing I do
is to preach.
I'm not a businessman. There are people
who are called anointed to do business.
THEY HAVE IDEAS TO DO BUSINESS. THEIR
MIND IS BUSINESS
BUT THEY CAN'T PREACH A SERMON. THAT
DOESN'T mean they can't speak. They can
speak as a secondary thing. Are you
hearing what I'm saying? BUT THEIR MAIN
CORE BUSINESS IS THEY KNOW WHO THEY ARE.
DO YOU KNOW WHO YOU ARE? BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T HAVE DOMINION IF YOU DON'T KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
This church needs to be paying me by the
way.
I'm serious. You need to be paying me
very good. Some CEOs take my message and
they say, "My goodness, you're teaching
this to your church. This is a master's
class in leadership.
I'm telling you the truth."
But tell me you teach this to your class
and some of you are just looking at me.
Giving you a master's class here which
you should be paying for at Strathmore.
You should know who you are.
You're not a slave.
You're a child of God. The Bible says
you're a son.
You're a son.
A slave fights for recognition. A son
knows they accepted.
A slave fights for access.
A son
fights from being accepted.
You are not a slave. Can you touch
somebody this afternoon and tell them
you're not a slave?
Who are you? Do you know yourself?
A slave lives in fear. A son lives in
inheritance.
SLAVE BEGS FOR ACCESS. SON knows he
belongs.
A slave struggles for acceptance. as a
son serves from acceptance.
Your identity determines your authority.
Sons and daughters of God carry kingdom
authority.
Dominion begins with knowing whose you
are. Dominion begins by knowing whose
you are.
Can I give you one more point?
Dominion requires responsibility.
Genesis chapter 2 and verse 15. And the
Lord God took the man and put him into
the Garden of Eden to dress it and to
keep it. To dress it and to keep it. You
cannot have dominion and you're doing
nothing.
You cannot have dominion and you have
not taken responsibility.
Some of you want authority, but you
don't want responsibility.
You cannot have. And the man took Adam
and put him in the garden and gave him
responsibility.
There must be something you're doing.
Touch your neighbor and tell them there
has to be something you're doing.
Anybody
who has dominion, whether it is in the
world circular, whatever it is, there's
something they're doing.
Alen Musk is developing Tesla cars.
Ellen Musk is taking people to the moon.
That's what he's working on and dreaming
about it and working his head off so
that he can go and take taking people as
tourists in the moon and Mars.
There must be something you're doing.
What are you doing?
Bill Gates did Microsoft and is still
doing it and developing and trying to
make it better.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU CANNOT talk about dominion, church.
Listen to me. You can be anointed until
the oil of KENYA PIPELINE IS FINISHED.
YOU CANNOT HAVE DOMINION AND YOU ARE
just there doing nothing.
Go to all the crusades you want to. You
will remember me.
Let them tell you the truth like I am
TELLING YOU. YOU CANNOT have dominion
and you have no responsibility.
I think the gospel was preached very
badly to charismatics
because you are taught faith faith faith
faith faith faith faith faith faith
faith faith and you're not taught works
works works works works AND BECAUSE
FAITH WITHOUT WORKS
HELLO FAITH WITHOUT WORKS YOU'RE NOT
taught that bit you're just taught faith
That's all you're taught.
But after you look at Marakumi, please
be responsible.
Hello.
Now, this summon is not good for lazy
people.
I'm very aware
because you have a lot of people who are
doing nothing.
This is not for you. You continue
sitting there. I'm preaching to people
who God has given the mandate to have
dominion and I'm giving them the steps
and the formulas of how it works.
You have to be able
to have responsibility.
Even Adam,
Adam had all the excuses to sit there
and do nothing.
BUT GOD SAYS NO.
WALK,
WALK.
I have never seen anybody who has
dominion, who has done nothing,
who is doing nothing. I've never come
across those kind of people. I've never
come across, maybe you have. I have not.
I have not. I've not been lucky to come
across people who are doing nothing.
Never.
So Luke 16 and verse 10 says, "He that
is faithful in that which is least is
faithful also in much."
That is the test. He that is faithful in
that which is least
is faithful in much. God gave Adam
authority over the garden,
but he also gave him responsibility for
the garden.
God
has given you the mandate to have
dominion.
And with that, he has entrusted you with
time.
He has entrusted you with talents.
He has entrusted you with resources.
He has entrusted you with relationships.
He has entrusted you with opportunities.
My brothers and sisters, we are managers
and not owners.
Faithfulness attracts greater
responsibility
and God promotes trustworthy stewards.
Dominion grows through obedience
and it grows through diligence.
Let me give you the last point very
quickly.
Dominion is restored
through Christ.
Romans chapter 5 and verse 17 says this
verse. I've been thinking about it the
whole week. By the way, I want you to
really look at it. They which receive
abundance of grace
and of the gift of righteousness.
What does it say?
They mine says they
which receive abundance of grace
and the gift
of righteousness shall do what?
Huh?
Huh? I can't hear you.
Okay, let's read it from the top. For if
by one's man's offense death reign by
one man, go ahead. Much more they which
receive abundance of grace, and of the
gift of what shall they do?
>> They shall reign in life by
>> by ONE JESUS CHRIST. YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO
BE REIGNING.
They that receive abundance of grace.
May you receive abundance of grace
today.
>> Can you shout amen?
>> May you receive abundance of grace
today? I say MAY YOU RECEIVE ABUNDANCE
OF GRACE TODAY. I SAY MAY YOU RECEIVE
ABUNDANCE OF GRACE TODAY. Can I hear a
thunderous amen?
shall reign in life
by one Jesus Christ. I've been thinking
about this verse the whole week
that if you have received grace
and the gift of righteousness shall you
shall reign in this life by one Jesus
Christ.
Jesus Christ
came
to restore what Adam lost.
For when Adam
ate the fruit, Adam lost dominion
through disobedience.
Sin entered the world.
Fellowship with God was broken.
Authority was compromised.
Death and bondage entered humanity.
But what Adam lost, Jesus restored.
Sin was defeated.
Satan was disarmed.
Authority was restored. Somebody say,
"Amen."
>> Believers can reign in life.
Yes. My brothers and sisters, ladies and
gentlemen,
Christ restored our position and
authority.
We are no longer to leave as slaves to
sin. Through Christ we reign in life.
Now I want to submit to you the mandate
has been given
and restored
in Jesus Christ.
God created humanity to reflect his
image,
walk in sunship,
steward his creation,
and exercise authority
under his rule.
This is a sermon series I want to preach
for one month and even more so that you
can understand
the works of redemption
in totality.
Because what's happening in the church
of Jesus Christ worldwide is appalling
to see people live in ignorance who
don't know who they are, who don't know
what Jesus has done for them and who
don't have dominion.
It is sad to see a sick poor church that
has no dominion.
God has called me to teach this and I
will teach it. Please don't let me down.
invite as many people as possible so
they can also partake
of this teaching. This is just the
introduction.
I've spoken for one hour. But if you can
stand up with me, I would like you to do
some declarations if that is okay with
you.
Are you ready? This one you have to
shout. Are you ready?
>> Yes.
I want you to open your mouth and shout
like you really believe it.
Say, I receive fresh revelation.
>> I receive fresh
>> of my God-given dominion.
>> of my Godgiven dominion.
>> Oh, say it again. I receive fresh
revelation. I receive
>> of my Godgiven dominion
>> of my Godgiven dominion.
>> Every limitation on my destiny
>> every
>> is broken now.
>> In Jesus name.
>> in Jesus name.
>> I'm not liking the way you're saying it.
I'm maybe I'm used to preaching to other
young churches, Pastor Jimmy and the
rest where there is life, vibrant people
who are living. I want vibrant people
here. Can you look at your neighbor and
say, "Are you living?" Can you I want
vibrant people when you say this. Can
you repeat this? Every limitation
>> every limitation
>> on my destiny
>> on my identity
>> is broken.
>> is broken
>> in Jesus name.
>> I walk in my identity
>> I walk in my
>> as a son
>> and heir
>> of God
>> of God. I shall faithfully
>> I shall faithfully
>> STEWARD EVERY BLESSING
>> steward every blessing
>> God has entrusted to me
>> God has entrusted TO ME
>> THROUGH CHRIST
>> I REIGN in this life
>> I reign IN THIS
>> THROUGH CHRIST
>> I REIGN IN THIS LIFE
>> I reign in this LIFE
>> AND I OVERCOME EVERY CHALLENGE
>> I over
>> in Jesus name
>> amen
>> PUT YOUR HANDS TOGETHER FOR JESUS JESUS.
HALLELUJAH.
HEY, what are you saying?
Hey,
you are meant TO HAVE DOMINION IN JESUS
NAME. You are SUPPOSED TO REIGN WITH
CHRIST IN THIS LIFE. YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO
WALK IN VICTORY IN THIS LIFE.
SATAN IS UNDER YOUR FEET IN THE NAME OF
JESUS.
>> HALLELUJAH.
Give Jesus a big clap offering.
Can I give you another one or two
declarations?
>> Yes.
>> Say it loud. I shall influence my
generation
>> I shall influence my generation.
>> For the kingdom of God
>> For the kingdom of God.
>> Fear
>> Failure
>> and defeat
>> shall not rule over me
>> shall not rule
>> Repeat that one. Fear
>> Fear,
>> failure,
>> AND DEFEAT
>> SHALL NOT RULE OVER ME.
>> shall not rule.
>> In Jesus name.
>> I have the victory.
>> I HAVE THE VICTORY.
THE LAST TIME I HAVE THE VICTORY.
>> AMEN.
>> To God be the glory.
From this day,
you walk in God's dominion. From this
day, can you shout amen?
>> From this day, you're not going as a
weakling, as somebody who's a victim.
No, you are going as a child of God who
operates in dominion in the mighty name
of Jesus. I say in the mighty name of
Jesus.
>> HALLELUJAH. MAY WHATEVER YOU TOUCH
PROSPER IN JESUS NAME.
MAY THE DECISIONS YOU MAKE BE INSPIRED
BY THE HOLY SPIRIT IN THE NAME OF JESUS.
You cannot be under the mercy of people
anymore.
>> Can you shout amen?
>> Amen.
>> I say you will not be under the mercy of
people anymore.
>> You will reign with Christ in this life.
>> YOU WILL REIGN WITH CHRIST IN THIS LIFE.
>> Next Sunday, don't miss.
I have got I don't know how many
messages on dominion. I am so annoyed in
the spirit.
In the spirit, I'm very annoyed when I
look at how Christians live. I am very
annoyed.
Very annoyed.
It's like Jesus never died for you.
It's like you're a victim every day,
every time.
No.
This is just the introduction.
So next Sunday bring people
next Sunday tell people let's go to
church. You know you I'll do the
preaching. You just do the inviting. I
cannot do both.
But he invite people and preach. I do
invite my friends sometimes and they
come
dominion.
Most of you, most of you came from very
poor families.
>> Is that true?
>> But you're changing the record. You
>> your children will be billionaires.
>> Out of your loins, children shall be
billionaires. You might have came, you
might come out from a place where they
didn't have money, BUT OUT OF YOUR
LOINS, THE RECORD IS CHANGING. I SAID
THE RECORD IS CHANGING.
That cycle will not continue.
>> I see it happening. I see it happening
in the spirit. It shall not continue.
>> Hallelujah. It will start with you. Oh,
come on. I want somebody to clap for G.
It will start with you.
ever true.
>> So next Sunday
we go we move fast far further.
It is my work to research and to read
the Bible. Your work is to bring sheep.
Sheep talks to sheep and the shepherd
will shepherd them.
>> Amen.
>> Please be seated in the presence of the
Lord.
It's time to worship God with our giving
hearts of praise.
>> Giving time is blessing time. Amen.
>> Prepare a good offering for God.
>> Those of you who are giving your tithe,
I know you know what you're going to
give. In fact, by the way, let me tell
you, by the time you leave your house,
you should know exactly what you're
coming to worship God with.